Guide to the Hartt Recording Studio records ARCH173
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
Hartt Recording Studio records
1953 - 1999
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
Hartt School. Hartt Recording Studio
ARCH173
3.33 Linear Feet (8 containers)
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to all researchers.
Biographical / Historical
The Hartt Recording Studio created an identification system to organize their recordings. The system is based on the date of the performance, using a three or four digit year number followed by a decimal point and a three-digit number representing both the month and day. Performances before 2000, dropped the thousands place of the year (i.e. a performance in 1999 would start with 999). Following the decimal was a number representing both the month and day. To shorten the length of the ID number to three numbers, months were represented with the following numbers: 100 – January, 150 – February, 200 – March, 250 – April, 300 – May, 350 – June, 400 – July, 450 – August, 500 – September, 550 – October, 600 – November, 650 – December.
The date was then added to the above month number to create the final three-digit month/date number (i.e. November 1 = 600 +1= 601 or December 15 = 650 + 15 = 665).
Examples:
January 5, 1957 = 957.105
February 5, 1962 = 962.155
February 15, 1988 = 988.165
When multiple recordings were made on the same day, letters or decimals were added to the end of the ID number to distinguish them.
Content Description
The collection consists of annotated programs for performances recorded by the Hartt Recording Studio. The annotations primarily provide the identification number(s) of the corresponding analog recordings, as well as the start and stop times of different portions of the performances on those recordings.
concert programs; Hartt School; Julius Hartt School of Music; Hartt College of Music
- Annotated programs, I
  - 1952-1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1965 Jan 6-May 28 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1965 Jun 1-Dec 15 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1967 Jan 4- May 29 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1967 Jun 7 - Dec 17 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1969 Jan 9- May 29 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1969 Jun 6- Dec 19 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1970 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1971 Jan 7- May 25 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1971 Jun 20- Dec 16 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1972 Jan 8- Apr 30 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1972 May 1- Dec 23 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1973 Jan 17- Apr 29 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1973 May 1 -Dec 14 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1974 Jan 20- Apr 30 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1974 May 1- Dec 9 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1975 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1976 Jan 22- May 15 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1976 Jun 14 - Dec 19 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1977 Jan 22- May 12 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1977 Jun 6- Dec 18 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1978 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1979 Jan 25- Sep 26 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 1979 Oct 2- Dec 15 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 1980 Jan 24- Jul 30 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 1980 Sep 21- Dec 14 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 1981 Jan 17- May 17 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1981 Jul 2 - Dec 14 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1982 Jan 21- Jun 27 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1982 Jul 16- Dec 14 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 1983 Jan 16- Mar 27 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 1983 Apr 7- Jun 26 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 1983 Jul 7-Dec 13 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 1984 Jan 12- Jun 27 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 1984 Jul 11-Dec 16 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 1985 Jan 20- Apr 30 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 1985 May 2- Dec 15 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 1986 Jan 11-May 18 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 1986 Jun 1- Dec 20 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 1987 Jan 23-May 31 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 1987 Jun 14-Dec 13 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - 1988 Jan 16- May 28 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 1988 Jul 22- 1989 Jan 31 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 1989 Feb 1-Jul 29 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 1989 Sep 8- Dec 11 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 1990 Jan 7-Jun 19 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 1990 Jul 10-Dec 18 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 1991 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 1992 Jan 19- Sep 27 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 1992 Oct 7-Dec 17 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 1993 Jan 10-Apr 30 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - 1993 May 1-Jul 31 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 1993 Aug 1-Dec 18 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 1994 Jan 16-Apr 29 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 1994 May 1-Dec 18 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 1995 Jan 7- May 20 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 1995 Jun 1-Dec 12 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 1996 Jan 6- Apr 30 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - 1996 May 1-Sep 29 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - 1996 Oct 4-Dec 20 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - 1997 Jan 11-Mar 27 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 1997 Apr 3-May 31 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 1997 Jun 1- Oct 28 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - 1997 Nov 7-Dec 20 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 1998 Jan 11-Mar 31 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 1998 Apr 1-Sep 27 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 1998 Oct 1-Dec 14 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 1999 Jan 19-Mar 31 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - 1999 Apr 1- May 23 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - 1999 Jun 1-Nov 17 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Undated (Box 8, Folder 11)